<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content id="ws_3385833966" name="Rescue Rangers" author="Chem O`Dun" version="101" date="2024-12-26" save="false" description="[h1][u]Rescue Rangers[/u][/h1]&#13;&#10;This extension allows you to rescue crews' members from the destroyed ships in a designated sector.&#13;&#10;Always the closest possible spacesuit will be selected to rescue. &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Compatibility[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;Compatible with [b]X4: Foundations 7.1[/b]. At least it written and tested with this version.&#13;&#10;Not created to use with fleets. It is a single ship script.&#13;&#10;Several ships with one script will work in one sector, but it is not tested properly.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Executing the order[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;You can select the order as any other, &quot;default&quot;, from the &quot;Navigation&quot; section of  orders.&#13;&#10;Please be aware - this order required the ship captain to have at least `one star` in the &quot;Pilot&quot; skill.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Configuration[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;There are a several configuration options available. You can see all of them on a screenshot.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Home Sector[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;This is a sector where the ship will rescue the crew. You can select it from the list of discovered sectors.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Home Station[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This is a station where the ship will be docked and wait for the next order. You can select it from the list of discovered stations in any sector.&#13;&#10;The best option is to select a station in the same sector as the Home Sector.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Ship - &quot;Dormitory&quot;[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This is a ship where the rescued crew will be placed. You can select it from the list of your ships. The ship should enough capacity to place all rescued crews' members.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Record to logbook[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will record the events to the logbook. I.e. starts, travel to desired sector, flying to the target, attacking the target, destroying the target, etc. &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Situation when both ships are full[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The ship's captain will periodically call to the player to inform about absence of the order. Additionally, if the Record to logbook is enabled - it will be recorded there as well.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Links[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;There is a thread on EgoSoft forum - [url=https://forum.egosoft.com/viewtopic.php?p=5259072][Mod/AIScript] Order &quot;Rescue Rangers&quot;[/url]&#13;&#10;" lastupdate="1734387688">
  <text language="7" name="Rescue Rangers" description="Rescue your crews in space"></text>
  <text language="33" name="Rangers de Sauvetage" description="Sauvez vos équipages dans l'espace"></text>
  <text language="34" name="Rescatadores" description="Rescata a tus tripulaciones en el espacio"></text>
  <text language="39" name="Rangers di salvataggio" description="Rescata a tus tripulaciones en el espacio"></text>
  <text language="44" name="Rescue Rangers" description="Rescue your crews in space"></text>
  <text language="49" name="Rettungs-Ranger" description="Rette deine Crew im Weltraum"></text>
  <text language="86" name="救援游骑兵" description="在太空中救援您的船员"></text>
  <text language="88" name="রেসকিউ রেঞ্জার্স" description="মহাকাশে আপনার ক্রুদের উদ্ধার করুন"></text>
  <text language="380" name="Рятувальники" description="Рятуйте свої екіпажі в космосі"></text>
</content>
