<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content
  id="ws_3385833966"
  name="Rescue Rangers"
  author="Chem O`Dun"
  version="106"
  date="2025-06-16"
  save="false"
  lastupdate=""
  description="This extension allows you to rescue crews' members from the destroyed ships in a designated sector.&#13;&#10;Always the closest possible spacesuit will be selected to rescue.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Compatibility[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Compatible with [b]X4: Foundations 7.1[/b]. At least it written and tested with this version.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Features[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Several ships with one order can work in one sector or crossed sectors.&#13;&#10;[b]Mimic[/b] order in a fleet is fully supported.&#13;&#10;From version 1.03 can work without [b]Home station[/b] set - in the [b]Fleet support[/b] mode.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]How it works[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The ship with order &quot;Rescue Rangers&quot; will wait docked in the Home Station or &quot;Dormitory&quot; ship for event, when any player ship in the Home Sector (or sector where the &quot;Dormitory&quot; is located) will be destroyed. After that, the ship will fly to find spacesuits and fly to it to rescue the crew's members.&#13;&#10;When the ship will collect all crew's members it will fly back to the Home Sector and dock to the Home Station or &quot;Dormitory&quot; ship.&#13;&#10;If case it will be full before the ship will collect all crew's members - it will try to transfer the rescued crew to the &quot;Dormitory&quot; ship and continue the rescue operation.&#13;&#10;If Rescue ship will return to the Home Station, it will not immediately transfer the rescued crew to the &quot;Dormitory&quot; ship. It will wait for the some period of &quot;silence&quot; before to do it.&#13;&#10;As in &quot;Fleet support&quot; mode it will dock to the &quot;Dormitory&quot; ship then it will transfer the rescued crew immediately after the docking.&#13;&#10;If the &quot;Dormitory&quot; ship will be full - the Rescue ship will try to inform you.&#13;&#10;Please don't forget to check the &quot;Dormitory&quot; ship and transfer the rescued crew to new ships.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Download[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;You can download the latest version via Steam client - [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3385833966]Rescue Rangers[/url]&#13;&#10;Or you can do it via the [url=https://www.nexusmods.com/x4foundations/mods/1571]Rescue Rangers[/url]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Executing the order[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;You can select the order as any other, &quot;default&quot;, from the &quot;Navigation&quot; section of  orders.&#13;&#10;Please be aware - this order requires the ship captain to have at least [b]one star[/b] in the &quot;Pilot&quot; skill.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Configuration[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;There are several configuration options available. You can see all of them on a screenshot.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Home Sector[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This is a sector where the ship will rescue the crew. You can select it from the list of discovered sectors.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Max gate distance to rescue[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This is a maximum distance from the Home Sector to the sector where the ship can rescue the crews' members. The ship will not react to ship destructions in the sectors further than this distance.&#13;&#10;Default value is [b]0[/b].&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Home Station[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This is a station where the ship will be docked and wait for the next order. You can select it from the list of discovered stations in any sector.&#13;&#10;The best option is to select a station in the same sector as the Home Sector.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If during setup the order the station was not selected, the ship will be in the [b]Fleet support[/b] mode. In this mode, the ship will dock to the &quot;Dormitory&quot; ship and will assume the current sector as the Home Sector for rescue operations.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Ship - &quot;Dormitory&quot;[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This is a ship where the rescued crew will be placed. You can select it from the list of your ships. The ship should have enough capacity to place all rescued crews' members.&#13;&#10;Please take into account - in the [b]Fleet support[/b] mode the &quot;Dormitory&quot; has to be capable to provide docking for the Rescuer ship.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Priority by oxygen remained[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This option allows you to select the priority of the rescue by the oxygen remaining in the spacesuit instead of the distance to the ship. If enabled, the ship will try to rescue the crews' members with the lowest oxygen remaining in the spacesuit.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Return them back on Replacement Ship[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, the rescued crew will be &quot;returned&quot; on the Replacement Ship, when it will rejoin to fleet.&#13;&#10;The [b]Lost Ships Replacement[/b] feature should be enabled for appropriate fleet commander or station. And for sure - the game version should be at least 7.50.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;There is one, but &quot;huge&quot;, limitation of this feature:&#13;&#10;[list]&#13;&#10;[*] Currently it is impossible to identify the commander of the destroyed ship. And there is no relation between destroyed and replacement ships.&#13;&#10;[*] [b]That's why the rescued crew will be assigned on the Replacement Ship with the same model as the destroyed ship and for the Commander closest to the Sector where the ship was destroyed.[/b]&#13;&#10;[/list]&#13;&#10;[b]Important note[/b]: This feature is configured on each Rescue ship separately!&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][b]Explanation video[/b][/h3]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[previewyoutube=OaU6-RikfnI;full][/previewyoutube]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Record to logbook[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will record the events to the logbook. I.e. starts, travel to desired sector, flying to the target, attacking the target, destroying the target, etc.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Situation when both ships are full[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The ship's captain will periodically call to the player to inform about absence of the order. Additionally, if the Record to logbook is enabled - it will be recorded there as well.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Links[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;There is a thread on EgoSoft forum - [url=https://forum.egosoft.com/viewtopic.php?p=5260786][Mod/AIScript] Order &quot;Rescue Rangers&quot;[/url]. Feel free to ask any questions or report issues there.&#13;&#10;">
  <text language="7" name="Rescue Rangers" description="Rescue your crews in space"></text>
  <text language="33" name="Rangers de Sauvetage" description="Sauvez vos équipages dans l'espace"></text>
  <text language="34" name="Rescatadores" description="Rescata a tus tripulaciones en el espacio"></text>
  <text language="39" name="Rangers di salvataggio" description="Rescata a tus tripulaciones en el espacio"></text>
  <text language="44" name="Rescue Rangers" description="Rescue your crews in space"></text>
  <text language="49" name="Rettungs-Ranger" description="Rette deine Crew im Weltraum"></text>
  <text language="86" name="救援游骑兵" description="在太空中救援您的船员"></text>
  <text language="88" name="রেসকিউ রেঞ্জার্স" description="মহাকাশে আপনার ক্রুদের উদ্ধার করুন"></text>
  <text language="380" name="Рятувальники" description="Рятуйте свої екіпажі в космосі"></text>
</content>